thespiritsbusiness.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy

**INTRODUCTION**

Welcome to Union Press’ privacy notice. Union Press Limited is the company that publishes of the The Drinks Business, The Drinks Business Hong Kong, Wine List Confidential, The Spirits Business, Greenkeeping and The Golf Business, as well as maintaining websites and publishing email newsletters for each of our titles.

Union Press respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our site (“Site”) receive our email newsletter (“Newsletter”) or subscribe to our print publication (“Magazine”) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

  1. **IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE**

This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Union Press collects and processes your personal data through your use of this Site or via our print-based Magazine, including any data you may provide through this Site when you sign up to our Site, browse or make a purchase via our Site or engage with us on our Site or through emails you may receive from us.

It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

CONTROLLER

Union Press Limited, the publisher of the The Drinks Business, The Drinks Business Hong Kong, Wine List Confidential, The Spirits Business, Greenkeeping and The Golf Business is the controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “Union Press”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).

We have appointed a data protection officer who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data protection officer using the details set out below.

CONTACT DETAILS

Full name of legal entity: Union Press Limited  
Email address: [dpo@unionpress.co.uk](mailto:dpo@unionpress.co.uk)  
Postal address: 4th Floor, Wigglesworth House, 69 Southwark Bridge Road, London SE1 9HH

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES

This version was last updated in May 2018. This policy may change and be updated from time to time. Please check back regularly.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

THIRD-PARTY LINKS

This Site includes advertisements and editorial links to third-party Sites. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party Sites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our Site, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

  2. **THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU**

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier.
  * **Contact Data** includes billing address, subscription delivery address and email address.
  * **Financial Data** includes bank account and payment card details.
  * **Transaction Data** includes details about payments from you to us for products and services you have purchased from our Site or Magazine.
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data (if you are registered on our SITE), browser type and version, time zone setting and general location, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this Site.
  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you.
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our Site, products and services collected for analytical purposes.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share **Aggregated Data** such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does **not** directly or indirectly reveal your identity. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

Except in limited circumstances which will be made clear to you, we do not collect any **Special Categories of Personal Data** about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, if we do not have access to your subscription address we can not provide you with the printed Magazine and we can not supply you with a daily Newsletter without your correct email address).

  3. **HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

**Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact, Transaction or Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, email telephone or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * create an account on our Site;
  * subscribe to our Magazine or email Newsletter;
  * interact with members of our sales, editorial or administrational staff; or
  * enter a Masters competition, purchase medal stickers, attend our Masterclass, Tasting or other events, book advertising space or sponsorship;

**Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our Site, our analytical service providers – Google Analytics and Google Doubleclick – may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns for statistical purposes. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. As you navigate our Site, we may collect Usage Data, Profile Data and Marketing and Communications Data as specified by you from time to time.

  4. **HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.

PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

What is a legitimate interest?

**Legitimate Interest** means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service and the best and most secure experience on our Site. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities on this link [here](https://www.thespiritsbusiness.com/legitimate-interest-statement/).

**Performance of Contract** means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party. If you fail to provide personal data that we require for the performance of a contract with you we cannot enter into a contract with you for the provision of our services.

** ** | **Activity/Purpose** | **Type of Data** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis for legitimate interest**  
---|---|---|---  
1. | Provide relevant trade information to you in print and online formats. This includes but is not limited to the information on our Site, and published in our Magazine and Newsletters | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

| Performance of a contract with you.  
2. | Answering and processing any claims or enquiries you may raise with us in connection with the Site, Magazine, Newsletter or in any transaction you may have undertaken with us. | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Transaction

| Necessary for our legitimate Interests to provide the most effective service to subscribers and advertisers and for evidential purposes in the event of a dispute.  
3. | Managing our relationship with you, for example: 

  * Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
  * Updating your details on our system, validating subscriptions or resetting a security question
  * in order to keep our records updated

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

(e) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests of updating customer details and preferences.  
5. | Promoting features on the Site, Magazine or Newsletter, such as: 

  * enabling you to partake in Masters competition or attend Masterclass, Tasting or other events
  * when you provide us with matter for use in the media
  * in order to study how subscribers use the products and services on our Site, Magazine or Newsletter;
  * to keep our records updated and to promote engagement with the Site, Magazine or Newsletter; and
  * to promote third party advertisers on the Site, Magazine or Newsletter

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| Necessary for our legitimate interests of promoting the Site and building our brand.  
6. | To administer and protect our business and this Site such as: 

  * troubleshooting
  * data analysis
  * testing
  * system maintenance
  * support
  * reporting and hosting of data

in order for the efficient running of the Site, provision of administration and IT services, network security.

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Financial

(e) Transactional

| Necessary for our legitimate interests of Site security  
7. | Providing business insight into how Subscribers use the Site. We do this by: 

  * delivering relevant Site content and advertisements to you and by measuring or understanding the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
  * using data analytics
  * making suggestions to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you

for the use of web analytics, profiling and personalisation in order to study how customers use our services, to develop them, to grow our business and to ensure our marketing strategy is as relevant and accurate as possible.

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

(f) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests in order to produce the most effective Site and member experience.  
|  |  |   
  
  5. **CHANGE OF PURPOSE**

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us at dpo@unionpress.co.uk

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so and give you the option to opt out of that usage.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

  6. **INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

Some of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area ( **EEA** ) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission.
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.

  7. **DATA SECURITY**

We are constantly reviewing appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

  8. **DATA RETENTION HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data.

  9. **YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.

You have the right to:

**Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you once we have identified that you are the correct person to release this information to.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have inadvertently processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
